<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<openerp>
	<data>
		<!-- === HWSETA Urges Caution When Enrolling at Private Training Institutions Page === -->
		<template id="news5" name="HWSETA Urges Caution When Enrolling at Private Training Institutions" page="True">
			 <t t-call="website.layout">
				<div id="wrap" class="oe_structure oe_empty">
					<div class="oc-sheet clearfix">
						<div class="oc-layout-wrapper">
							<div class="oc-content-layout">
								<div class="oc-content-layout-row">
	
									<t t-call="hwseta_website.sidebar1" />
								
									<div class="oc-layout-cell oc-content">
										<article class="oc-post oc-article ">
											<div class="oc-postcontent oc-postcontent-0 clearfix">
												<div class="navigation">
													<div class="alignleft">
														«
														<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=642" title="HWSETA Achieves Clean Audit for 2013/14 Financial Year"
															rel="prev">HWSETA Achieves Clean Audit for 2013/14 Financial Year</a>
													</div>
													<div class="alignright">
														<a href="/page/hwseta_website.news4"
															title="Qualification Development and Maintenance a Key Focus for the HWSETA"
															rel="next">Qualification Development and Maintenance a Key Focus for the
															HWSETA</a>
														»
													</div>
												</div>
											</div>
									
									
										</article>
										<article id="post-903"
											class="oc-post oc-article  post-903 post type-post status-publish format-standard hentry category-latest-news">
											<h1 class="oc-postheader">HWSETA Urges Caution When Enrolling at Private Training
												Institutions</h1>
											<div class="oc-postheadericons oc-metadata-icons">
												<span class="oc-postdateicon">
													<span class="date">Published</span>
													<span class="entry-date" title="2:21 pm">February 4, 2015</span>
												</span>
												|
												<span class="oc-postauthoricon">
													<span class="author">By</span>
													<span class="author vcard">
														<a class="url fn n" href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?author=7"
															title="View all posts by Elfrieda Tyrer">Elfrieda Tyrer</a>
													</span>
												</span>
											</div>
											<div class="oc-postcontent oc-postcontent-0 clearfix">
												<p>
													The South African Sector Education and Training Authorities (SETAs)
													on a daily basis receive reports of students that have been the
													victims of unscrupulous training providers. Whilst this is a
													national problem, the Health and Welfare Sector Education and
													Training Authority (HWSETA) is currently very concerned about the
													actions of several unscrupulous training or skills development
													providers operating in Kwa-Zulu Natal that claim to have the
													necessary accreditation from the HWSETA. These organisations have
													been reported to the relevant law enforcement agencies.
													<span id="more-903"></span>
												</p>
												<p>Investigations by the HWSETA following reports by stakeholders
													have identified the following more common issues: false claims that
													the training facility is accredited with the HWSETA; offering
													courses for which the facility does not have accreditation;
													exceeding enrolment capacity; as well as the issuing of fraudulent
													certificates.</p>
												<p>“Parents and learners are urged to contact the HWSETA before
													enrolling with any private training institution that claims to be
													accredited by the HWSETA,” comments Ms Yvonne Mbane, CEO for the
													HWSETA, “even if the provider in question makes use of the HWSETA
													logo in marketing materials.”</p>
												<p>The accreditation status of a training provider and/or the courses
													it offers can be confirmed by calling the HWSETA’s toll free
													helpline on 0800 864 478. Alternatively, contact the HWSETA in KZN
													on 031 202 5972/3.</p>
												<p>It needs to be noted that the HWSETA has no jurisdiction over any
													nursing qualifications as they fall within the ambit of the South
													African Nursing Council (SANC) that can be contacted on 012 420
													1075.</p>
												<p>“As the HWSETA, we are mandated to protect the rights of learners
													in this country and we encourage stakeholders to contact us on our
													toll free helpline if they have any queries or concerns.” concludes
													Ms Mbane.</p>
											</div>
									
									
										</article>
									
									
									</div>
									
									<t t-call="hwseta_website.sidebar2" />
	
								</div>
							</div>
						</div>
					</div>
				</div>
			</t>
		</template>
	</data>
</openerp>