<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" ?>
<openerp>
	<data>
		<!-- === Current News Page === -->
		<template id="current_news" name="Current News" page="True">
			<t t-call="website.layout">
				<div id="wrap" class="oe_structure">
					<div class="oc-sheet clearfix">
						<div class="oc-layout-wrapper">
							<div class="oc-content-layout">
								<div class="oc-content-layout-row">

									<t t-call="hwseta_website.sidebar1" />

									<div class="oc-layout-cell oc-content">
										<article class="oc-post oc-article  breadcrumbs">
											<div class="oc-postcontent oc-postcontent-0 clearfix">
												<h4>Latest News</h4>
											</div>
								
								
										</article>
										<article id="post-1143"
											class="oc-post oc-article  post-1143 post type-post status-publish format-standard hentry category-latest-news">
											<h1 class="oc-postheader">
												<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=1143" rel="bookmark"
													title="Expressions of Interest for 2015 – 2016 Now Open">Expressions of Interest for 2015 – 2016 Now Open</a>
											</h1>
											<div class="oc-postheadericons oc-metadata-icons">
												<span class="oc-postdateicon">
													<span class="date">Published</span>
													<span class="entry-date" title="11:15 am">July 31, 2015</span>
												</span>
											</div>
											<div class="oc-postcontent oc-postcontent-0 clearfix">
												<p>
													EOI Bursaries for Employed Persons 2015-2016
													<br/>
														EOI Internships 2015-2016
														<br/>
															EOI Work Experience for TVET Learners 2015-2016
															<br/>
																EOI Learnerships 2015-2016
																<br/>
																	EOI Sign Language for Department of health and Social
																	Development Employees 2015-2016
																	<br/>
																		EOI Skills Programmes 2015-2016
																		<br/>
																			EOI Work Integrated Learning 2015-2016
												</p>
												<p>
													<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?page_id=48">click here</a>
													to redirect to the Expression of Interest Information
												</p>
											</div>
								
								
										</article>
										<article id="post-1094"
											class="oc-post oc-article  post-1094 post type-post status-publish format-standard hentry category-latest-news">
											<h1 class="oc-postheader">
												<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=1094" rel="bookmark"
													title="SkillsTalk@HWSETA Newsletter June 2015 edition out now">SkillsTalk@HWSETA Newsletter June 2015 edition out now</a>
											</h1>
											<div class="oc-postheadericons oc-metadata-icons">
												<span class="oc-postdateicon">
													<span class="date">Published</span>
													<span class="entry-date" title="3:26 pm">June 29, 2015</span>
												</span>
											</div>
											<div class="oc-postcontent oc-postcontent-0 clearfix">
												<p>
													<a
														href="/hwseta_website/static/src/wp-content/uploads/2015/06/skillstalk_hwseta-june-2015-final.pdf">Click here </a>
													to download newsletter
												</p>
											</div>
								
								
										</article>
										<article id="post-1018"
											class="oc-post oc-article  post-1018 post type-post status-publish format-standard hentry category-latest-news">
											<h1 class="oc-postheader">
												<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=1018" rel="bookmark"
													title="HWSETA Funds Animal Health Studies in Eastern Cape">HWSETA Funds Animal Health Studies in Eastern Cape</a>
											</h1>
											<div class="oc-postheadericons oc-metadata-icons">
												<span class="oc-postdateicon">
													<span class="date">Published</span>
													<span class="entry-date" title="10:18 am">May 28, 2015</span>
												</span>
											</div>
											<div class="oc-postcontent oc-postcontent-0 clearfix">
												<p>At a function held in Tsolo, Eastern Cape, on 25 May 2015 the
													Health and Welfare Sector Education Training Authority (HWSETA)
													awarded 50 learners with full bursaries to obtain a Diploma in
													Animal Health from the Tsolo Agricultural and Rural Development
													Institute (TARDI).</p>
												<p>The event was attended by the Deputy Minister of Higher Education
													and Training, Honourable Mduduzi Manana, the MEC for Eastern Cape
													Rural Development and Agrarian Reform, Mr Mlibo Qoboshiyane, the
													Mayor of Mhlontlo Local Municipality, Counsellor M Giyose, Chariman
													of the HWSETA Board, Dr Confidence Moloko, Ms Yvonne Mbane, CEO for
													the HWSETA, numerous other dignitaries, the learners and their
													parents.</p>
												<p>“The partnership that the HWSETA has entered into with the
													Eastern Cape Department of Rural Development and Agrarian Reform is
													a significant milestone in pushing back the frontiers of poverty,”
													comments Ms Mbane.</p>
												<p>Ms Mbane describes the partnership as ‘business unusual’, but is
													quick to add that this is a strategic intervention specifically
													aimed at addressing the shortage of skills in the animal health
													sector, which contributes towards food security.</p>
												<p>19-year-old Wandile Sitandatu trekked more than a 100km from Kei
													Mouth to Tsolo earlier this year with one goal in mind, to become
													an animal health technician. He successfully registered for the
													three-year diploma at TARDI but he held out little hope that his
													unemployed mother would be able to afford the tuition fees of R20
													000 per year.</p>
												<p>“Immediately after I received the fee structure for my studies,
													my knees just went weak and I thought this is it for me, this is
													the end of my dream,” Sitandatu explained to the audience with
													tears in his eyes. “When I got home I showed my grandmother the fee
													structure and she also agreed we wouldn’t be able to pay.”</p>
												<p>This all changed for the better when he was one of the 50
													students who would receive funding from the HWSETA for his studies.
													Sitandatu believes that the bursary he has received from the HWSETA
													will open many doors for him.</p>
												<p>Mr Qoboshiyane urged the learners to grab the opportunity with
													both hands. He described how his Department is intent on turning
													the Eastern Cape into a hub of activity and a food basket.</p>
												<p>Learners and their parents alike were overwhelmed and expressed
													their joy and gratitude. One learner was given the opportunity to
													thank the HWSETA saying that ‘I do not know where I would have gone
													to or what I would’ve become if it was not for the bursary. My
													grandmother does not work, and with this I will be giving her hope
													too that the suffering will one day end’.</p>
											</div>
								
								
										</article>
										<article id="post-991"
											class="oc-post oc-article  post-991 post type-post status-publish format-standard hentry category-latest-news">
											<h1 class="oc-postheader">
												<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=991" rel="bookmark"
													title="Qualification Development and Maintenance a Key Focus for the HWSETA">Qualification Development and Maintenance a Key Focus for the
													HWSETA</a>
											</h1>
											<div class="oc-postheadericons oc-metadata-icons">
												<span class="oc-postdateicon">
													<span class="date">Published</span>
													<span class="entry-date" title="1:23 pm">April 23, 2015</span>
												</span>
											</div>
											<div class="oc-postcontent oc-postcontent-0 clearfix">
												<p>The skills development landscape in South Africa is one that
													requires constant change and innovative thinking on the part of
													Sector Education Training Authorities (SETAs) to meet the needs of
													the sectors they serve. The HWSETA is no exception and it is this
													mindset that resulted in the establishment of the Qualification
													Development and Maintenance (QDM) sub-division in October 2013 to
													focus on this key area of responsibility for the HWSETA.</p>
												<p>“The delivery of quality training in South Africa requires a
													combination of accredited training providers that are able to
													deliver excellent quality training content and material,” comments
													Champa Gopal, Qualification Development and Maintenance Manager for
													the HWSETA. “By assessing and maintaining quality in these two
													critical areas, learners in South Africa are assured that the
													training they receive will enable them to make a positive
													contribution to the skills pool in the health and social
													development sectors.”</p>
												<p>Since its establishment, the QDM sub-division has approached the
													task at hand with zest and the hard work is paying off.</p>
												<p>The QDM sub-division, in partnership with the National Department
													of Health (NDOH) and International Training Education Centre for
													Health (I-TECH), has been successful at registering the
													Occupational Qualification: Health Promotion Officer (Community
													Health Worker) SAQA ID 94597 in November 2014. This qualification
													replaces three community health work (CHW) legacy qualifications in
													the form of CHW levels 2, 3 and 4.</p>
												<p>The HWSETA will not accredit private skills development providers
													(SDPs) for this newly registered occupational qualification and
													this is a function that will reside with the Quality Council for
													Trades Occupation (QCTO). Accreditation of providers by the QCTO
													will be dependent on the signing of a Memorandum of Understanding
													with the National Department of Health (NDOH) ensuring the learner
													has a designated workplace with a mentor during the time of study
													to obtain the required workplace experience.</p>
												<p>Ms Gopal adds that the accreditation processes for legacy
													qualifications will remain with the HWSETA and this should not be
													confused with the accreditation processes outlined by QCTO for
													registered occupational qualifications.</p>
												<p>The HWSETA conducted workshops nationally to inform its
													stakeholder base of this shift in accreditation and implementation
													processes for this new occupational qualification, as well as
													qualifications that will be developed in future.</p>
												<p>To date the QCTO has successfully accredited twelve regional
													training centers attached to the NDOH. A partnership pilot training
													project for 900 learners in twelve regional training centres
													commenced in March 2015.</p>
												<p>Whilst the HWSETA will not be responsible for the accreditation
													Skills Development Providers for this occupational qualification,
													it has received approval from the QCTO to be the Assessment Quality
													Partner (AQP). As an AQP, the HWSETA is responsible for setting up
													final external summative examinations, co-ordination of national
													examinations through approved assessment centers, as well as
													assessment and recommendation of learner certification to QCTO.</p>
												<p>The examination process and logistical arrangements will be
													conducted through partnerships with Community of Experts (CEP’s) to
													ensure seamless quality processes are applied. The ETQA will
													timeously announce all examination logistics.</p>
												<p>“This is an important milestone for the HWSETA and we believe
													that what we have learnt during this process will pave the way for
													the development of occupational qualifications that will replace
													the thirty three legacy qualifications that the HWSETA is mandated
													to quality assure,” adds Ms Gopal.</p>
												<p>The HWSETA has submitted the occupational qualification, Social
													Auxiliary Work to QCTO for registration with SAQA and is currently
													awaiting the outcome of this occupational qualification.</p>
												<p>Within the next five years the HWSETA intends having all legacy
													qualifications re-curriculated into qualifications that will
													translate into occupations and ultimately provide the youth of the
													country an opportunity to follow a career within the Health or
													Social Services Sector .</p>
												<p>“The development of occupational qualifications that are relevant
													to the labour market underpins the activities of the QDM
													sub-division and it is this thinking that drives us to achieve
													targets that will positively impact the health and social
													development sectors in the country,” concludes Ms Gopal.</p>
												<p> 
												</p>
											</div>
								
								
										</article>
										<article id="post-903"
											class="oc-post oc-article  post-903 post type-post status-publish format-standard hentry category-latest-news">
											<h1 class="oc-postheader">
												<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=903" rel="bookmark"
													title="HWSETA Urges Caution When Enrolling at Private Training Institutions">HWSETA Urges Caution When Enrolling at Private Training
													Institutions</a>
											</h1>
											<div class="oc-postheadericons oc-metadata-icons">
												<span class="oc-postdateicon">
													<span class="date">Published</span>
													<span class="entry-date" title="2:21 pm">February 4, 2015</span>
												</span>
											</div>
											<div class="oc-postcontent oc-postcontent-0 clearfix">
												<p>
													The South African Sector Education and Training Authorities (SETAs)
													on a daily basis receive reports of students that have been the
													victims of unscrupulous training providers. Whilst this is a
													national problem, the Health and Welfare Sector Education and
													Training Authority (HWSETA) is currently very concerned about the
													actions of several unscrupulous training or skills development
													providers operating in Kwa-Zulu Natal that claim to have the
													necessary accreditation from the HWSETA. These organisations have
													been reported to the relevant law enforcement agencies.
													<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=903#more-903" class="more-link">
														Continue reading
														<span class="meta-nav">→</span>
													</a>
												</p>
											</div>
								
								
										</article>
										<article id="post-642"
											class="oc-post oc-article  post-642 post type-post status-publish format-standard hentry category-frontpage category-latest-news">
											<h1 class="oc-postheader">
												<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=642" rel="bookmark"
													title="HWSETA Achieves Clean Audit for 2013/14 Financial Year">HWSETA Achieves Clean Audit for 2013/14 Financial Year</a>
											</h1>
											<div class="oc-postheadericons oc-metadata-icons">
												<span class="oc-postdateicon">
													<span class="date">Published</span>
													<span class="entry-date" title="7:36 am">November 4, 2014</span>
												</span>
											</div>
											<div class="oc-postcontent oc-postcontent-0 clearfix">
												<p>
													When the South African Auditor-General awards a public entity a
													clean audit it is an indication of exemplary achievement in terms
													of corporate governance, risk management, consistent application of
													internal control,
													<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=642#more-642" class="more-link">
														Continue reading
														<span class="meta-nav">→</span>
													</a>
												</p>
											</div>
								
								
										</article>
										<article id="post-202"
											class="oc-post oc-article  post-202 post type-post status-publish format-standard hentry category-latest-news">
											<h1 class="oc-postheader">
												<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=202" rel="bookmark"
													title="Skills Development for Persons with Disabilities a Focus for HWSETA">Skills Development for Persons with Disabilities a Focus for
													HWSETA</a>
											</h1>
											<div class="oc-postheadericons oc-metadata-icons">
												<span class="oc-postdateicon">
													<span class="date">Published</span>
													<span class="entry-date" title="12:52 pm">October 9, 2014</span>
												</span>
											</div>
											<div class="oc-postcontent oc-postcontent-0 clearfix">
												<p>
													As part of its skills development mission, the HWSETA strives to
													create an awareness of disability and how employing persons with
													disability can enrich the working environment, as well as the lives
													of those living with disability.
													<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=202#more-202" class="more-link">
														Continue reading
														<span class="meta-nav">→</span>
													</a>
												</p>
											</div>
								
								
										</article>
										<article id="post-100"
											class="oc-post oc-article  post-100 post type-post status-publish format-standard hentry category-latest-news">
											<h1 class="oc-postheader">
												<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=100" rel="bookmark"
													title="Stakeholder Interaction Remains a Key Driver for HWSETA">Stakeholder Interaction Remains a Key Driver for HWSETA</a>
											</h1>
											<div class="oc-postheadericons oc-metadata-icons">
												<span class="oc-postdateicon">
													<span class="date">Published</span>
													<span class="entry-date" title="1:52 pm">September 19, 2014</span>
												</span>
											</div>
											<div class="oc-postcontent oc-postcontent-0 clearfix">
												<p>
													In striving to meet the needs of learners in the health, social
													development and veterinary sectors, the HWSETA realises the
													importance of maintaining effective stakeholder communication that
													guides the direction skills development initiatives should be
													taking.
													<a href="http://www.hwseta.org.za/?p=100#more-100" class="more-link">
														Continue reading
														<span class="meta-nav">→</span>
													</a>
												</p>
											</div>
										</article>
									</div>
									
									<t t-call="hwseta_website.sidebar2" />

								</div>
							</div>
						</div>
					</div>
				</div>
			</t>
		</template>
	</data>
</openerp>